Guide to the Office on the Education of Women, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Office on the Education of Women, Yale University, records
1968-1977
RU 821
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
21.5
(51 boxes)
The records of Office on the Education of Women (formerly the Coeducation Office) document all aspects of Yale University's transition to undergraduate coeducation, as well as the status of women at Yale and women in academe. Planning for incorporating women in Yale College and the residential colleges, admissions, and the first undergraduate female students are particularly well documented. The records include correspondence, memoranda, reports, meeting agendas and minutes, admission applications and other student data, and printed articles and news clippings, primarily maintained by the Special Assistant to the President on the Education of Women.
Yale University. Office on the Education of Women
Arnstein, Margaret G.
Wasserman, Elga (Elga Ruth)
Yale University. Coeducation Office
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 2-B (YRG 2-B), Records of Yale presidential assistants.
General note
Former title: Elga Wasserman as Special Assistant to the President of Yale University for the Education of Women records.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the Yale University Office on the Education of Women, 1975 and by Elga Wasserman, 2006.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is partially restricted. See the Collection Contents for details.
Appraisal
Routine administrative and financial records are not maintained based on departmental policy.
Biographical / Historical
Kingman Brewster, president of Yale University, announced in 1968 that Yale would admit 500 women into Yale College in the following Fall. The impact of coeducation at Yale was far reaching, in addition to the integration of female students into Yale College and the residential colleges, services and regulations such as housing, dining, parietal rules, and health services were examined and changed as necessary. Additionally, a small number of new services and programs were created, such as gynecological services, sex counseling, and courses on human sexuality. Coeducation brought other women's issues at Yale, including women faculty and women's studies, to the forefront.
Brewster appointed Elga Wasserman as Special Assistant to the President on the Education of Women to serve as advisor and to oversee the planning and implementation of coeducation in its undergraduate program. Wasserman chaired the Planning Committee on Coeducation (1968-1969), which oversaw every aspect of planning. In 1969, the University Committee on Coeducation was formed and was also chaired by Wasserman. The Committee continued to oversee the transition and facilitate integration of the female students. The Coeducation Office, headed by Wasserman, was also established to facilitate programs initiated by the Committee and to serve as a resource for the undergraduates, as well as graduate students, other women on campus, and administrators.
Wasserman left Yale in 1972. Mary Arnstein became Acting Special Assistant to the President and chair of the University Committee on Coeducation. The Committee voted to terminate the position of Special Assistant and the Coeducation Office and transfer responsibilities to existing offices and a reorganized University Committee on the Education of Women in 1973. Some functions of the Coeducation Office were assumed by the new Office on the Education of Women. The University Committee on the Education of Women served as an advisory group to the president on issues related to women at Yale until 1977. There was a separate University Council Committee on the Education of Women that was a Yale Corporation Committee.
Scope and Contents
The records of Office on the Education of Women, including records of the Special Assistant to the President on the Education of Women, document all aspects of Yale University's transition to undergraduate coeducation. Operations and programs of Yale College and the residential colleges were most directly impacted by the change. Planning for incorporating women in undergraduate life, admissions, and the first undergraduate female students are particularly well documented. The records, arranged alphabetically by topic, include correspondence, memoranda, reports, meeting agendas and minutes, admission applications and other student data, and printed articles and news clippings. In addition to administrative files, the records include subject files related to women and women's issues maintained as a resouce by the Coeducation Office. Researchers interested in women at Yale, coeducation, and women in academe will find the records a rich resource.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession and topically therein as received from the creating office.
Coeducation; Universities and colleges -- Admission; Women college students; Women -- Education; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Admission; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Coeducation Office; Yale University. Office on the Education of Women; Yale University. President's Office
- Topical Files, 1968-1974; Accession 19ND-A-086
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 2 to 16 and 40 to 47 are restricted, because they contain student and personnel records. Restrictions are indicated at the file level.
  - A-Z, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Restricted, 1970, 1974 (Box 40, Folder 1086)
  - Abortion, 1971 (Box 40, Folder 1087)
    Materials restricted until January 1, 2041 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - Academe, general, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Academic women, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Restricted (Box 40, Folder 1088)
      Materials restricted until January 1, 2048 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - Admissions
    - Admissions Committee, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
    - Class of 1975 - Class of 1977, 1969-1972 (Box 40, Folder 1090-1092)
      Restricted until January 1, 2053 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - Correspondence and research, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Graduate and professional, 1972 (Box 40, Folder 1093)
      Restricted until January 1, 2048 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - Pilot Program, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Policy, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Procedure, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Statistics
      - General, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - Restricted (Box 40, Folder 1094)
          Restricted until January 1, 2049 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
      - Class of 1972, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Class of 1973, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Class of 1974, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Class of 1975, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        - Restricted (Box 40, Folder 1095)
          Restricted until January 1, 2047 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
      - Class of 1976, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Student data cards
      - Housing preferences, 1969 (Box 2)
        Restricted until January 1, 2050 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
      - Majors, circa 1971-1972 (Box 3)
      - Transfers, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
    - Student files
      - Class of 1971
        - General, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 16)
        - Individuals
        - Withdrawals
      - Class of 1972
        - General, circa 1969 (Box 7, Folder 221)
        - Individuals
        - Withdrawals
      - Class of 1973
        - Individuals
        - Withdrawals
      - Class of 1974
        - General, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 606)
        - Copies of Admissions Form I, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 607)
        - Individuals
        - Withdrawals
      - Class of 1975, financial aid candidates, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 841-842)
        Restricted until January 1, 2051 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
      - Class of 1976
        Restricted until January 1, 2052 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
        - A-F, 1970-1972 (Box 14, Folder 843-849)
        - G-Z, 1970-1972 (Box 15, Folder 850-865)
    - Students
      - Data sheets, including class rank and test scores, circa 1971 (Box 40, Folder 1096-1097)
      - Intended major, class of 1973 (female), 1969 (Box 16, Folder 866)
      - Male candidates for class of 1974, final actions, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 867)
      - Male candidates for class of 1975, 1971 (Box 47, Folder 1157-1159)
      - Transfers
        - General, 1969, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 868-869)
        - Juniors, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 870)
        - Sophomores, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 871)
    - Survey, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 872)
    - Transfer
      - Policy, 1968-1972 (Box 17, Folder 873)
        - Restricted (Box 40, Folder 1098)
      - Procedure, 1968-1972 (Box 40, Folder 1099)
      - Statistics, circa 1968-1972 (Box 17, Folder 874)
  - Affirmative Action, 1971-1974 (Box 17, Folder 875-876)
  - Alumni
    - General, 1970-1973 (Box 17, Folder 877-878)
    - Data cards, undated (Box 18)
  - Alumni Fund, 1971-1972 (Box 19, Folder 879)
  - American Association of University Women
    - General, 1969-1981 (Box 19, Folder 880-884)
    - Nominations, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 885)
    - Recognition Award, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 886)
  - Arts, 1970-1971 (Box 19, Folder 887)
  - Assistants to master, 1969-1974 (Box 40, Folder 1100)
    Materials restricted until January 1, 2050 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - Bathrooms, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 888)
  - Black students, 1968-1972 (Box 19, Folder 889)
    - Restricted (Box 41, Folder 1101)
  - Black women and the Liberation Movement, 1970-1972 (Box 20, Folder 890)
  - Billing
    - General, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 891)
    - Requests for books, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 892)
  - Budget
    - General, 1969-1972 (Box 20, Folder 893-896)
    - Bursary, 1968-1973 (Box 41, Folder 1102)
  - Child care program, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 898)
  - Coeducation
    - Office library, bibliography, circa 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 899)
    - Philosophy, 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 900)
    - Studies, 1968-1970 (Box 20, Folder 901)
    - Newspaper clipping photocopies, 1969-1970 (Box 48)
  - Coeducation, University Committee on
    - General, 1970-1973 (Box 21, Folder 902-906)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1971 (Box 21, Folder 907)
    - Materials distributed, 1969-1971 (Box 22, Folder 908-909)
    - Report, 1969-1974 (Box 22, Folder 910-913)
  - Committee on Human Sexuality, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 914)
  - Community relations, 1971-1972 (Box 22, Folder 915)
  - Crank mail, 1969-1972 (Box 23, Folder 916)
  - Davie study, 1969-1970 (Box 23, Folder 917)
  - Day care, 1969-1970 (Box 23, Folder 918-919)
    - Restricted, 1971 (Box 41, Folder 1103)
  - Development and sex differences, 1970-1971 (Box 41, Folder 1104-1105)
  - Economics, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 920)
  - Education
    - Coeducation, 1971-1972 (Box 23, Folder 921)
    - Women and academia, 1968-1972 (Box 23, Folder 922)
    - Women's education, 1970-1972 (Box 24, Folder 923-924)
  - Employment, 1965-1970 (Box 24, Folder 925)
    - Restricted (Box 41, Folder 1106)
  - Enrollment statistics for Yale, 1969-1972 (Box 24, Folder 926)
  - Extra-curricular activities, 1969-1971 (Box 24, Folder 927)
  - Federal funding, 1969-1970 (Box 24, Folder 928)
  - Fellows, 1970-1972 (Box 24, Folder 929)
  - Feminism and socialism, 1968-1970 (Box 25, Folder 930)
    - Restricted, 1971 (Box 41, Folder 1107)
  - Film on coeducation, 1969-1971 (Box 25, Folder 931)
  - Financial aid, 1969-1972 (Box 41, Folder 1108-1109)
  - Ford Foundation, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 932)
  - Freshman advising, 1971-1972 (Box 25, Folder 933)
    - Restricted (Box 41, Folder 1110)
  - Freshman counselors, 1969-1970 (Box 42, Folder 1111)
  - Freshman mailings, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 934)
  - Freshman orientation, 1971-1972 (Box 25, Folder 935-936)
  - Gift account, 1968-1974 (Box 42, Folder 1112)
  - Graduate advisors
    - General, 1970-1972 (Box 25, Folder 937)
      - Restricted, 1970-1973 (Box 42, Folder 1113-1116)
    - Applicants for 1971-1972
      - General, 1971-1972 (Box 42, Folder 1117)
      - Girls who applied late and seniors applying, 1968-1971 (Box 43, Folder 1118)
      - No letters sent, 1971 (Box 43, Folder 1119)
    - Applicants for 1972-1973
      Materials restricted until January 1, 2049 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
      - General, 1971-1972 (Box 43, Folder 1120)
      - No letters sent, 1971-1972 (Box 43, Folder 1121)
    - Reserve, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 1122)
  - Graduate School, 1968-1973 (Box 25, Folder 938-939)
  - H, 1969-1970 (Box 43, Folder 1123)
  - Health, 1969-1973 (Box 26, Folder 940-941)
    - Restricted (Box 43, Folder 1124)
  - Hillman, James, lecture, undated (Box 26, Folder 942)
  - History
    - General, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 943)
      - Restricted, circa 1969-1973, and undated (Box 43, Folder 1125-1126)
        Restricted until January 1, 2050
    - Black women, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 1127)
  - Housing
    - General, 1969-1971 (Box 26, Folder 944-947)
    - General, 1971-1973 (Box 27, Folder 948-950)
    - By college, 1970-1971 (Box 27, Folder 951)
      - Restricted (Box 43, Folder 1128)
    - Colleges and halls
      - Berkeley College, 1968-1969 (Box 27, Folder 952)
      - Branford College, 1968-1969 (Box 27, Folder 953)
      - Calhoun College, 1968-1970 (Box 27, Folder 954)
      - Davenport College, 1969-1971 (Box 27, Folder 955)
        - Restricted (Box 43, Folder 1129)
      - Timothy Dwight College, 1969-1971 (Box 27, Folder 956)
      - Timothy Dwight College Annex, 109 Grove Street, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 957)
      - Jonathan Edwards College, 1968-1970 (Box 27, Folder 958)
      - Helen Hadley Hall, 1968-1971 (Box 28, Folder 959)
      - Morse College, 1968-1970 (Box 28, Folder 960)
      - Pierson College, 1969-1970 (Box 28, Folder 961)
      - Pierson College Annex, 87 Howe Street, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 962)
      - Ezra Stiles College, 1968-1969 (Box 28, Folder 965)
      - Trumbull College, 1969-1970 (Box 28, Folder 966)
    - Complaints, 1970-1972 (Box 28, Folder 967)
    - Patterns, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 968)
      - Restricted, 1971-1972 (Box 43, Folder 1131)
    - Questionnaire, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 969)
      - Restricted (Box 43, Folder 1132)
  - Humanities, 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 970)
  - Incoming women, booklet for, 1968-1970 (Box 29, Folder 971-972)
  - Information on coeducation, requests for, 1970-1972 (Box 29, Folder 973-976)
  - Information on coeducation, requests for, 1971-1973 (Box 30, Folder 977-979)
  - Intercollegiate Association of Women Students, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 980)
  - Laundry, 1968-1969 (Box 30, Folder 981)
  - Law, 1967-1971 (Box 30, Folder 982)
  - Legal rights, discrimination
    - General, 1970-1972 (Box 30, Folder 983)
      - Restricted (Box 43, Folder 1133)
    - Administrators' wives and administrators, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 984)
    - Affirmative action, 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 985)
    - Fair employment practices, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 986)
  - Legislation, Executive Order 11246, circa 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 987)
  - Literature, women and myth, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 1134)
  - Maintenance contracts, 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 988)
  - Majors, class of 1971 and class of 1972 (Box 44, Folder 1135-1136)
  - Marriage, lifestyles, and family
    - Family, circa 1971 (Box 31, Folder 989)
      - Restricted, 1970 (Box 44, Folder 1137)
    - Marriage and alternative lifestyles, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 990)
      - Restricted, circa 1970-1971 (Box 44, Folder 1138-1139)
    - Maternity leave policies, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 991)
  - Media and sex role socialization
    - Children, 1970-1971 (Box 44, Folder 1140-1141)
    - Women, 1970-1971 (Box 45, Folder 1142)
  - Medicine, 1969-1971 (Box 31, Folder 992)
  - Mental health and women, 1970 (Box 45, Folder 1143)
  - Morality, 1970-1971 (Box 45, Folder 1144)
  - Names, maiden and married, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 993)
  - O, 1968-1969 (Box 45, Folder 1145)
  - Occupational fields, miscellaneous, 1970-1972 (Box 31, Folder 994)
  - Office of Educational Research, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 995)
  - Office of Institutional Research, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 996)
  - Onat, Etta, "A Man and Two Women" by Doris Lessing, circa 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 997)
  - Orientation, 1969-1970 (Box 31, Folder 998-999)
  - Parents' Weekend, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 1000)
  - Parientals, 1967-1970 (Box 32, Folder 1001)
  - Personnel policies, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 1002-1003)
  - Professions and management, 1969-1971 (Box 32, Folder 1004)
    - Restricted (Box 45, Folder 1146)
  - Public service, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 1005)
  - Ratio, male/female, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 1006)
  - Reports, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 1007)
    - Restricted, 1973 (Box 45, Folder 1147)
  - Schwartz and Lever study, undated (Box 33, Folder 1008)
  - Science, 1971-1972 (Box 33, Folder 1009)
  - Sex course, sex counseling, 1969-1971 (Box 33, Folder 1010)
  - Social science, 1971-1972 (Box 33, Folder 1011)
  - Special students, 1969-1970 (Box 33, Folder 1012)
  - Statistics
    - Miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 1013)
    - Post college, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 1014-1015)
    - Raw data, circa 1974 (Box 45, Folder 1148)
  - Student unrest, 1969-1972 (Box 34, Folder 1016)
    - Restricted (Box 45, Folder 1149)
  - Summer programs, 1969-1971 (Box 34, Folder 1017)
  - Taft Hotel, 1968 (Box 34, Folder 1018)
  - Third world women, circa 1971 (Box 45, Folder 1150)
  - Transfers, by previous college, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 1019)
  - Undergraduate Housing Subcommittee, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 1020)
  - Undergraduate Schools Committee, 1969-1972 (Box 34, Folder 1021)
  - University Committee on the Education of Women, 1973-1974 (Box 34, Folder 1022-1024)
  - University Housing Committee, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 1025)
  - Vacation policy, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 1026)
  - Vanderbilt Hall, 1968-1971 (Box 35, Folder 1027)
  - Withdrawals, leaves, 1970-1971 (Box 45, Folder 1151)
  - Women and achievement, 1968-1972 (Box 35, Folder 1030)
    - Restricted (Box 45, Folder 1152)
  - Women and aging, 1970-1971 (Box 46, Folder 1153)
  - Women and work, 1957-1973 (Box 35, Folder 1031)
    - Restricted (Box 46, Folder 1154)
  - Women's Advisory Council, 1969-1974 (Box 35, Folder 1032-1037)
  - Women's courses, inquiries about, 1970-1973 (Box 35, Folder 1038)
  - Women's liberation, 1970-1973 (Box 36, Folder 1039)
    - Restricted (Box 46, Folder 1155)
  - Women's literature, bibliographies, circa 1967-1972 (Box 36, Folder 1040-1041)
  - Women's programs, colleges and universities with
    - Amherst College, circa 1966-1968 (Box 36, Folder 1042)
    - Arizona State University, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 1043)
    - Barnard College, 1968-1972 (Box 36, Folder 1044)
    - Boston College, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 1045)
    - Brandeis University, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 1046)
    - Brown University, Pembroke College, 1969-1972 (Box 36, Folder 1047)
    - California Institute of Technology, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 1048)
    - California, University of, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 1049)
    - Cambridge-Goddard Graduate School for Social Change, circa 1972 (Box 36, Folder 1050)
    - Cedar Crest College, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 1051)
    - Chicago, University of, 1968-1970 (Box 37, Folder 1052)
    - Cincinnati, University of, undated (Box 37, Folder 1053)
    - Columbia University, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 1054)
    - Connecticut, University of, 1971 (Box 37, Folder 1055)
    - Cornell University, circa 1969-1970 (Box 37, Folder 1056)
    - Dartmouth College, 1968-1972 (Box 37, Folder 1057)
    - Hampshire College, undated (Box 37, Folder 1058)
    - Harvard-Radcliffe Policy Committee, Report on Coeducation, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 1059)
    - Harvard University, 1971-1973 (Box 37, Folder 1060)
    - Haverford College, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 1061)
    - Indiana University, 1971-1972 (Box 37, Folder 1062)
    - Jackson College for Women, Tufts University, 1970-1972 (Box 37, Folder 1063)
    - Mount Holyoke College, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 1064)
    - Notre Dame, University of, 1972 (Box 37, Folder 1065)
    - Pomona College, undated (Box 37, Folder 1066)
    - Princeton University, 1969-1972 (Box 38, Folder 1067-1068)
    - Quinnipiac College, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 1069)
    - Skidmore College, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 1070)
    - Smith College, 1948, 1969-1971 (Box 38, Folder 1071)
    - Stanford University, circa 1968-1973 (Box 38, Folder 1072)
    - Swarthmore College, 1968-1972 (Box 38, Folder 1073)
    - Wellesley College, 1969-1971 (Box 38, Folder 1074)
    - Wesleyan University
      - General, 1970-1972 (Box 38, Folder 1075)
      - Special admissions cases, 1967-1969 (Box 38, Folder 1076)
    - Williams College, 1970 (Box 39, Folder 1077)
    - Miscellaneous colleges, 1968-1971 (Box 39, Folder 1078)
  - Woodrow Wilson Fellowships, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 1079)
  - Yale and women's self-concept, 1969, and undated (Box 39, Folder 1080)
    - Restricted, 1971 (Box 46, Folder 1156)
  - Yale clubs, 1969-1972 (Box 39, Folder 1081)
  - Yale Health Plan
    - General, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 1082)
    - Problems and complaints, 1971-1972 (Box 39, Folder 1083)
  - Yale Mortgage Loan Plan, circa 1968 (Box 39, Folder 1084)
  - Yale Non-Faculty Action Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 39, Folder 1085)
- Records concerning coeducation and affirmative action at Yale, 1968-1995; Accession 2006-A-213
  Scope and Contents
  Includes some personal and post-tenure files of Elga Wasserman.
  Box 4 is restricted until January 1, 2024. The remainder of the accession is open for research.
  - Advisory Committee on Coeducation, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Coeducation Office, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Coeducation at Yale, 1968-1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 4 - 5)
  - Greene Committee: Committee on the Status of Women at Yale, 1971-1972, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Study Group on Yale College, 1972, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Women at Yale, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 8 - 9)
  - Films, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Mory's, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - National Merit Scholarship, 1970, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - President and provost, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Women faculty -general, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ph.D. survey, undated (Box 1, Folder 15 - 16)
  - Women's colleges, 1969-1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - HEW, 1970-1972, undated (Box 1, Folder 18 - 19)
  - Women at Yale -clippings, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Berkeley College seminar: "Educated Women", 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Affirmative action
    - General, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 22 - 23)
    - Yale, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 24 - 25)
    - Other universities, 1970-1973, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Affirmative action plan -Yale, 1971-1973, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Princeton -affirmative action, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 28 - 29)
  - Women in higher education -background, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 30 - 31)
  - Women in the labor force data, 1966-1973 (Box 2, Folder 32 - 35)
  - Status of professional women, 1970-1977 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Professional women's groups, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Bibliographies on history/status of women, 1968-1972, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Personal, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Yale Corporation, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    Corporation records are restricted until January 1, 2024 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - Yale coeducation anniversaries, 1976-1995 (Box 5, Folder 41-42)